Guide to the Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Alphabetical, Series I
  - Day, Caleb: 2 manuscripts, 1818, undated (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - Day, George Edmund: Transferred to Gad Day Family Papers, Mss 1225 (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Day, Jeremiah: correspondence, poetry, 1815-1864 (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - Day, Julian: poem, clippings, 1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 217)
  - Day, Mills: letters of recommendation addressed to Day and others, records of grades, 1810-1811 (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - Dean, Gilbert: ALS to H.J. Beetfield: Transferred To Misc MSS D, undated (Box 6, Folder 219)
  - DeForest, John U. Hyde: ALS to E[dward] S. Dana, Transferred to Dana Family Papers, Mss 164, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 220)
  - DeForest, Lee: Transferred to Lee DeForest Papers, Mss 1210 (Box 6, Folder 221)
  - DeForest, Othniel: 5 ALS to Edward Shippen, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 222)
  - Degrees and honors - Yale: Photostatic copy of ALS from T. Woodbridge, lists of "Junior Appointments", 1718, 1836-1838, 1851 (Box 6, Folder 223)
  - DeLancey, John D.: ALS to Samuel Hitchcock, 1814 (Box 6, Folder 224)
  - Deming, Julius, Jr.: essays, receipts, account book, betting book, 1797, 1799, undated (Box 6, Folder 225)
  - Derby, William M.: sketch of his Yale room, 1882-1883 (Box 6, Folder 226)
  - Dering, Henry Pacter: photostatic copy of ALS from Benjamin F. Thompson, 1784 (Box 6, Folder 227)
  - Dickinson, Baxter: account book: Transferred to Misc MSS D, 1813 (Box 6, Folder 228)
  - Dickinson, James T.: Transferred to James T. Dickinson Papers, Mss 183 (Box 6, Folder 229)
  - Dickinson, John Dean: ALS to Vosburgh (?), 1800 (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - Dickinson, Samuel Henry: ALS to Oscar Keeler, 1856 (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Dixon, Ephraim W.: typescript account of a tornado in Omaha, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 232)
  - Dodd, Lee Wilson: autographed typescript of play, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - Donnelly, James E.: correspondence concerning Donnelly, 1902-1917 (Box 6, Folder 234)
  - Donnelly, James E.: autobiographical sketch, [ca. 1912-1914] (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - Douglas, Newhall: ALS to "Dear Ronald", 1938 (Box 6, Folder 236)
  - Douglas, William Kirtland: photostatic copy of ALS to H.W. Shove, 1848 (Box 6, Folder 237)
  - Downes, John J.H.: ALS to ___Bishop, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 238)
  - Downes, William Elijah: correspondence, 1868, 1895 1897 (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - Driver, Cecil: Transferred to Cecil Driver Papers, Mss 782 (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - Dudley, Samuel W.: correspondence and printed matter: Transferred to S.W. Dudley Papers, MS 1086, 1947-1955 (Box 6, Folder 241)
  - Dudley, Samuel W.: "Report of the President's Committee on General Education": Transferred to S.W. Dudley Papers, MS 1086, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 242)
  - Dun, Alan A.: drawing, [ca.1938-1942] (Box 6, Folder 243)
  - Durand, Henry S.: Autographed copy of "Bright College Years", ALS to Ely Buell, clippings, 1928, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 244)
  - Dutton, Chester: correspondence, 1883-1885, undated (Box 6, Folder 245)
  - Dwight Hall: "Records of the Class Prayer Meetings and other religious statistics of 1894 - 1898 - 1902", 1891-1898 (Box 7, Folder 246)
  - Dwight, Timothy (1752-1817): correspondence, psalms and hymns, slave bond, library privilege list, "Analysis of Dwight's Theology" -- Transferred to Dwight Family Papers, Mss 187, 1797-1826, undated (Box 7, Folder 247)
  - Dwight, Timothy (1778-1844) correspondence, receipts -- Transferred to Dwight Family Papers, Mss 187, 1800-1832 (Box 7, Folder 248)
  - Dwight, Timothy (1828-1916): correspondence -- Transferred to Dwight Family Papers, Mss 187, 1853-1910 (Box 7, Folder 249)
  - Eccles, John: 2 ALS (photostatic copies) to his mother, undated (Box 7, Folder 250)
  - Edward VIII: ALS from Edward VIII's secretary to Anson Phelps Stokes, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 251)
  - Edwards, Alfred L.: ALS to William E. Hulbert, 1890 (Box 7, Folder 252)
  - Edwards, Benjamin: ALS to Stephen Edwards, three bills for college expenses, 1823-1828 (Box 7, Folder 253)
  - Edwards, Franklin: bills and other papers of Yale interest, 1872-1874 (Box 7, Folder 254)
  - Edwards, Jonathan: "Oratorio Valedictoria Habita In Aula Accademica", undated (Box 7, Folder 255)
  - S.S. Elihu Yale: correspondence regarding the S.S. Elihu Yale, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 256)
  - Eliot, Ellsworth: correspondence, 1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 257)
  - Eliot, Gustavus: "Ezra Stiles, D.D.," typescript drafts of a paper read before the New Haven Colony Historical Society with corrections and additions, [1926] (Box 7, Folder 258)
  - Elkin, William L.: correspondence, diaries, photographs and other material relating to Elkin, director of Yale Observatory, 1896-1910, 1874-1940, undated (Box 7, Folder 259)
  - Ellsworth, Henry Leavitt: Transferred to Henry L. Ellsworth Papers, Mss 197 (Box 7, Folder 260)
  - Ely, Ezra Stiles: ALS to Charles Brown, 1833 (Box 7, Folder 261)
  - Epsilon Association: papers relating to the building of a fraternity house, 1905-1906 (Box 7, Folder 262)
  - Esty, Isaac: ALS to Elisha Sands Plumb with notes and covering letters, 1816 (Box 7, Folder 263)
  - Evans, Alexander W.: ALS to John C. Tracy, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 264)
  - Evarts, John Jay: list of classmates, "Catalogue of the Officers and Students in Yale College," "Statement of Facts Pertaining to the Case of Yale College", 1831-1832 (Box 7, Folder 265)
  - F.W. [possibly William Frazier Y.1832]: translation of Latin passage, 1829 (Box 7, Folder 266)
  - Fabrique, Charles: Transferred to Fabrique Family Papers, Ms 201 (Box 7, Folder 267)
  - Farnam, Henry: Letters and papers relating to Yale University: Transferred to Farnam Family Papers, Mss 203, 1862-1874 (Box 7, Folder 268)
  - Farnam, Henry W.: correspondence and notes regarding prize essay competitions Transferred to Henry W. Farnam Papers Mss 470, 1912-1916 (Box 7, Folder 269)
  - Farnam, Thomas W.: ALS to Thomas Farnam from Edwin M. Herr with carbon of reply, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 270)
  - Farr, Charles E.: "Notes on Mosquitoes and Malaria in New Haven," rough draft of his graduation essay, Yale memorabilia, 1893-1903 (Box 7, Folder 271)
  - Farrand, Beatrix: ALS to Mrs. George P. Day, undated (Box 7, Folder 272)
  - Faulkner, Herbert Waldron: Letters from Van Vection Waring and Everett Meeks and a newspaper clipping concerning Faulkner, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 273)
  - Faulkner, Joseph W. [pseudonym for Endress Faulkner]: ALS to Daniel Wight, 1834 (Box 7, Folder 274)
  - Ferris, David: ALS to Arthur Twining Hadley from Mary G. Swift concerning Ferris, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 275)
  - Ferry, Charles H.: ALS to Lynde A. Catlin concerning the Yale boathouse, 1874 (Box 8, Folder 276)
  - Field, Maunsell B.: ALS to W.P. [Fessenden?], 1862 (Box 8, Folder 277)
  - Finch, Francis M.: poem about Andersonville, undated (Box 8, Folder 278)
  - Fisher, George P.: ALS from William H. Freemantle, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 279)
  - Fisher, George W.: marriage certificate of George and Elmira (Wescott) Fisher, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 280)
  - Fisher, Thomas R.: autograph album presented to him upon his leaving the Bristol Company, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 281)
  - Fitch, Eleazur: ALS to Rev. David D. Field, church certificates: Transferred to Field Family Papers Mss 630 3/82 NR, 1832-1843 (Box 8, Folder 282)
  - Fitch, Eleazur T.: ALS to Hezekiah Howe, 1816 (Box 8, Folder 283)
  - Fitch, James: photostat of "The Yale Grant" by Julia Pettee, undated (Box 8, Folder 284)
  - Fitch, John S.: pencil and crayon sketch of New Haven, 1870 (Box 8, Folder 285)
  - Fitzgerald, John H.: MS of "Chauncey Brewster Tinker and little me", undated (Box 8, Folder 286)
  - Flourney, Thomas N.: letters to Professor Carl F. Schreiber, 1940-1945 (Box 8, Folder 287)
  - Foch, M. Ferdinand: autograph, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 288)
  - Fook, Edwin B.: ALS to T.D. Woolsey, 1866 (Box 8, Folder 289)
  - Ford, Guy S.: ALS to Andrew Keogh concerning Yale curriculum, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 290)
  - Fowler, William C.: ALS to Addison Van Name with petition from the tutors written in 1822, Circa 1875 (Box 8, Folder 291)
  - Frank, Clinton: ALS to Hollon Farr, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 292)
  - Freshman Laws, undated (Box 8, Folder 293)
  - Frick, Jackson: letters to J.H. Samson, 1864-1865 (Box 8, Folder 294)
  - Friedman, Stanleigh P.: TLS to L.H. Baker, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 295)
  - Frost, Cleveland: TLS to Robert L. Clark, letters of condolence, 1918-1919 (Box 8, Folder 296)
  - Fuller, Clement A.: TLS to Hollon Farr concerning Blacks at Yale, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 297)
  - Fuller, Thomas: petitions to the General Assembly, 1761 (Box 8, Folder 298)
  - Fulton, John F.: letters to Maria T. Dana: Transferred to Dana Family Papers Mss 164, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 299)
  - Gaby, Alan: musical spoofs of Yale, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 300)
  - Gage, Brownell: news release concerning Gage, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 301)
  - Gale, Harlow: MS describing his education, Circa 1936 (Box 8, Folder 302)
  - Garman, Charles E.: drawing of his room at the Yale Divinity School, Circa 1879 (Box 8, Folder 303)
  - Gay, Julius: disciplinary notices, photographs, letters, sketches from friend, clippings, 1854-1859 (Box 8, Folder 304)
  - Gaylord, Franklin A.: poem, "Fifty Years After" for the 50th reunion of the Class of 1876, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 305)
  - Gee, John A.: TLS from Hoyt H. Hudson with review, ALS from Paul S. Clarkson, 1938, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 306)
  - Gemehl, Jacques C.: diary, 1930-1931 (Box 8, Folder 307)
  - Gibbs, Josiah W.: ALS from Yale officials, 1826 (Box 8, Folder 308)
  - Gillespie, Thomas H.: 2 ALS to A. Guyot Cameron, 1941, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 309)
  - Gittingham, R.P.: ALS to Robert J. Johnson, 1843 (Box 8, Folder 310)
  - Glyuna Boat Club: receipts, 1860-1866 (Box 8, Folder 311)
  - Gnade, Richard E.: Ms describing his junior year fellowship, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 312)
  - Goddard, George W.: correspondence, 1841-1847 (Box 8, Folder 313)
  - Goodhart, Arthur L.: speech, undated (Box 8, Folder 314)
  - Goodloe, Robert W.: TLS to H.H. Tweedy, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 315)
  - Goodrich, Chauncey A.: correspondence, 1835-1855 (Box 8, Folder 316)
  - Goodrich, Chauncey S.: ALS to George Parmly Day from Francis Dodge concerning Goodrich, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 317)
  - Goodrich, Elizur: ALS to J.M. Clayton and petition to Goodrich: Transferred to Goodrich Family Papers Mss 242,11/82, 1783, 1849 (Box 8, Folder 318)
  - Goodrich, James R.: [exam?], undated (Box 8, Folder 319)
  - Goodwin, Edwin: 28 college compositions, 1820-1823 (Box 8, Folder 320)
  - Grant, John Mason: tuition and board bills and other papers, 1829-1837 (Box 9, Folder 321)
  - Gray, Philip H.: TLS to Clive Day, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 322)
  - Gregory, Herbert E.: TLS from Franklin Delano Roosevelt with carbon of Gregory's letter, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 323)
  - Gridley, Frederick: ALS to Isaac Bird, 1817 (Box 9, Folder 324)
  - Griffin, George: essays, 1820-1824, undated (Box 9, Folder 325-326)
  - Griscom, John: ALS to Jeremiah Day, 1824 (Box 9, Folder 327)
  - Griswold, Alfred Whitney: ALS to George Parmly Day, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 328)
  - Griswold, Freeman Clark: essay "Washington Irving", 1879 (Box 9, Folder 329)
  - Griswold, Jared: Ms speech, B.A. and M.A. diplomas, financial papers, affidavits concerning his right to practice law, and other papers, 1815-1835 (Box 9, Folder 330)
  - Grosvenor, Thomas Peabody: ALS to William Brown, 1811 (Box 9, Folder 331)
  - Gulliver, Henry Strong: genealogy, undated (Box 9, Folder 332)
  - Hale, Enoch: photostat of 12 diary pages, letter "to all concerned", 1773, 1809 May 13 (Box 9, Folder 333)
  - Hale, Nathan: photostat of ALS to his brother, 1767 (Box 9, Folder 334)
  - Hale Nathan: TLS to Theodore Sizer from Edward Everett Hale, enclosing "Nathan Hale - A Word Portrait", also 10 ALS to Henry P. Johnson, and ALS to Mr. Morse, 1880-1901, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 335)
  - Hall, Lovell: TLS "My Old College Clock", certificate appointing him commissioner of Middlesex County Superior Court, 1906, undated (Box 9, Folder 336)
  - Hall, Willis: ALS to Samuel B. Ruggles, 1899 (Box 9, Folder 337)
  - Halsted, William S.: statements concerning him, 1922, undated (Box 9, Folder 338)
  - Hamilton, George H.: TLS to Donald G. Wing, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 339)
  - Hamilton, Thomas L.: ALS from Chauncey M. Depew to Anson Phelps Stokes on his behalf, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 340)
  - Hand, Learned: TMS speech at Elizabethan Club, TLS to Bernhard Knollenberg, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 341)
  - Harland, Edward: ALS to William L. Hinman, 1852 (Box 9, Folder 342)
  - Harrison, Carter Henry (1825-1893): 8 ALS to his mother, 1842-1845 (Box 9, Folder 343)
  - Harrison, Carter Henry (1860-): TLS to James T. Babb, TLS from Babb, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 344)
  - Harvard-Yale Club, Berlin: list of those registered, 1897-1898 (Box 9, Folder 345)
  - Harwood, Asa Frank: ALS to his brother and sister, 1849 (Box 9, Folder 346)
  - Hawthorne, Alexander T.: ALS to Dorothy W. Bridgwater from Craig Mathews and Dalton Georgia concerning Hawthorne, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 347)
  - Hays, Southard: receipt, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 348)
  - Hays, Thomas A.: MS address on intemperance, undated (Box 9, Folder 349)
  - Hazen, Allen T.: correspondence, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 350)
  - Hebard, Morgan: biographical material, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 351)
  - Heermance, T. Woolsey: memorandum as to disposal of effects, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 352)
  - Hemingway, Jacob: ALS concerning Hemingway, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 353)
  - Hess, George: ALS to the President of the law school at Yale College, [1881] (Box 9, Folder 354)
  - Hess, William Milton: recommendations of Hess's book, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 355)
  - Hewes, David: typed copy of a letter to his mother, Ruth H. Swain, 1847 (Box 9, Folder 356)
  - Hewitt, John H.: TMS of address at dedication of Sprague Hall, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 357)
  - Hibbard, Harry Dudley: ALS to his father, 1877 (Box 9, Folder 358)
  - Hicock, Henry Walter: "Memo on Earnings from Forest Plantations" (1924), correspondence, 1924-1968 (Box 9, Folder 359)
  - Hill, Raymond T.: ALS to the Secretary of Yale University, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 360)
  - Hillhouse, James (1754-1832): ALS to Henry Davis, receipt for $60 from Titus Street for interest on subscription towards support of a theological professor -- Transferred to Hillhouse Fam. Papers, 1804, 1823 (Box 9, Folder 361)
  - Hillhouse, James (1854-1938): Columbia College Law School prize essay -- Transferred to Hillhouse Fam. Papers, 1878 (Box 9, Folder 362)
  - Hinckley, Asa Josiah: ALS (photostatic copy) to Abby Ann Jepson, 1832 (Box 9, Folder 363)
  - Hinckley, Henry R.: typed copies of 9 letters to his parents: Transferred to H.B. Hinckley Papers, No. 1230, 1858 (Box 9, Folder 364)
  - Hinkle, Thornton M.: correspondence, 1887, 1894 (Box 9, Folder 365)
  - Hirsh, Allan M.: carbon copy of TL to Carl A. Lohmann, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 366)
  - Hitchcock, Samuel J.: "Oration on American Literature": Transferred to Samuel J. Hitchcock Papers Mss 1184, 1814 (Box 9, Folder 367)
  - Hoffman, Malvina: ALS to Mrs. Charles P. Howland concerning Jean Julien Lemordant, recipient of the Howland Prize: Transferred to Charles B. Howland Papers Mss 292 4/83 NR, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 368)
  - Hogan, Charles Beecher: track certificate, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 368a)
  - Holbrook, Levi: letters to George Platt, 1859-1873 (Box 10, Folder 369)
  - Holcomb, Hiram: correspondence, 1828-1840 (Box 10, Folder 370)
  - Holcombe, Harold G.: lecture notes, Circa 1895 (Box 10, Folder 371)
  - Holliday, Charles K.: ALS from [?] Rochel, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 372)
  - Hollister, George W.: 2 ALS to Charles G. Graves, [1845?], undated (Box 10, Folder 373)
  - Holmes, Abiel: ordination proclamation, ALS to ordination council from Holmes, other papers relating to the ministry, 1785-1791, 1812 (Box 10, Folder 374)
  - Holmes, Eliphalet: ALS from John Pratt and Israel Brainerd, 1795, 1810 (Box 10, Folder 375)
  - Holmes, Isaac E.: ALS to [J.T. Mason?], 1848 (Box 10, Folder 376)
  - Holmes, Silas: ALS to Jabez Holmes, his father, regarding college life and expenses, 1831 (Box 10, Folder 377)
  - Honeywood, St. John: sketches and certificate, undated (Box 10, Folder 378)
  - Hooker, Brian: poem "1919" and ALS to Victor Sutro with poem, undated (Box 10, Folder 379)
  - Hooker, John: ALS to Samuel Cowles and two diaries/ memoranda books, 1789-1833 (Box 10, Folder 380)
  - Hopkins, [E. Washburn? ]: Transferred to Hopkins Family Papers, Mss 290 (Box 10, Folder 381)
  - Hopkins, Samuel: notes of sermons preached by Reverend Breck, Hopkins and Pell, 1735 (Box 10, Folder 382)
  - Hoppin, James M.: correspondence, passport, sketch, printed matter, 1859-1917 (Box 10, Folder 383)
  - Hosmer, Stephen T.: ALS to Nathan Smith, ALS to Nehemiah Hubbard, notes on a case, 1798, 1806, undated (Box 10, Folder 384)
  - Howard, Ezekiel: photostat of letter to his parents, 1814 (Box 10, Folder 385)
  - Howard, Henry W.B.: photostat and transcript of ALS to his mother, 1870 (Box 10, Folder 386)
  - Howard, James: ALS to his sister, Lucy, 1805 (Box 10, Folder 387)
  - Howe, Elmer P.: two prize compositions, 1874 (Box 10, Folder 388)
  - Howe, Samuel: bill for subscription payment for Yale College fund, 1832 (Box 10, Folder 389)
  - Howell, George R.: correspondence (among the correspondents are Timothy Dwight and Theodore Woolsey), 1853-1898 (Box 10, Folder 390)
  - Howland, Henry E.: Transferred to the Charles P. Howland Family Papers, Mss 292 (Box 10, Folder 391)
  - Hubbard, John S.: chemistry notes taken in Benjamin Silliman's class, 1818 (Box 10, Folder 392)
  - Hubbard, Samuel: Transferred to the Daniel Hubbard Family Papers, Mss 970 (Box 10, Folder 393)
  - Humphreys, May: TLS to Gilbert M. Troxell: Transferred to Misc MSS H, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 394)
  - Hunt, William H.: ALS to William H. Law, [1914?] (Box 10, Folder 395)
  - Huntington, Asahel: ALS to unidentified correspondent, 1838 (Box 10, Folder 396)
  - Huntington, D.: ALS to Augustus R. Street, 1864 (Box 10, Folder 397)
  - Huntington, Henry: letters from his brother Jedidiah and others, 1829-1833 (Box 10, Folder 398)
  - Huntington, Henry S.: certificate of admission to Yale College, ALS to Rev. F. W. Bur-?, 1853, 1858 (Box 10, Folder 399)
  - Hyatt, Willard C.: correspondence and diary about Yale athletics, 1900-1916 (Box 10, Folder 400)
  - Inner Temple: minute book, correspondence, notes, 1897, undated (Box 11, Folder 401)
  - Ives, Charles: ALS to his father, Eli Ives, 1829 (Box 11, Folder 402)
  - Ives, Eli: "Abel Y. Sizer's Notes on Ive's Lectures", two invitations, 1820, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 403)
  - Ives, Levi: ALS to his father, Eli Ives, 1840 (Box 11, Folder 404)
  - Ives, Matthew: ALS to Oliver Root, 1821 (Box 11, Folder 405)
  - Ives, Robert S.: autograph album, Wooden Spoon oration, 1855, 1862 (Box 11, Folder 406)
  - Jackson, Joseph C.: ALS to Arthur T. Hadley, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 407)
  - Jackson, Samuel Cram: 2 ALS to his sister Susan, 1822 (Box 11, Folder 408)
  - James, Henry A.: ALS from Leonidas Points to the Examining Board of Yale College recommending James for entrance in the sophomore class, 1870 (Box 11, Folder 409)
  - Jamison, John Henry: certificate of membership in Zeta Psi, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 410)
  - Jarvis, Samuel Farmar: Transferred to Kingsley Papers, Mss 604 (Box 11, Folder 411)
  - Jennings, William J.: account book, 1839-1843 (Box 11, Folder 412)
  - Johnson, Leeds: three certificates from the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1892-1894 (Box 11, Folder 413)
  - Johnson, Sir William M.: ALS to General Thomas Gage, 1768 (Box 11, Folder 414)
  - Johnson, William Samuel: "Oratorio Cliosophica", undated (Box 11, Folder 415)
  - Johnston, Henry Phelps: 2 ALS to Henry Phelps Johnston from various Yale classmates, diary, 1863-1868 (Box 11, Folder 416)
  - Johnston, John: letter and article concerning chemistry at Yale, 1923-1924 (Box 11, Folder 417)
  - Johnston, William Preston: ALS to E.T. Lee, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 418)
  - Jones, Charles: ALS to his brother, A. M. Jones, 1843 (Box 11, Folder 419)
  - Jones, Edwin Pitkin: 6 ALS from Rufus C. Crampton, 5 ALS from Andrew Upson, 1843-1851 (Box 11, Folder 420)
  - Jones, Frank Hatch: genealogical material, undated (Box 11, Folder 421)
  - Jones, Frank J. and Charles D. Jones: photostatic copies of letters from various correspondents, including William Howard Taft, 1856-1929 (Box 11, Folder 422)
  - Jones, John Nelson: correspondence concerning Jones, biographical and genealogical material (photostatic copies), 1632, 1939, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 423)
  - Jones, Thomas A. B.: ALS to "Dear Bert", 1917 (Box 11, Folder 424)
  - Joy J.R.: Transferred to Hollon Farr Papers, Mss 910 (Box 11, Folder 425)
  - Karrick, David Brewer: Transferred to the David Brewer Karrick Papers, Mss 7 (Box 11, Folder 426)
  - Keller, Albert Galloway: correspondence, 1928-1950 (Box 11, Folder 427)
  - Keller, Charles R.: advertisement for tutoring, undated (Box 11, Folder 428)
  - Kellogg, Stephen Wright: ALS to Ben Perly Poore, 1875 (Box 11, Folder 429)
  - Kelly, William Cody: "Physical Preparedness" (carbon of typescript), undated (Box 11, Folder 430)
  - Kent, James: 5 letters to Ebenezer Foote with 3 DS authorizing Charles Foote to practice law in New York State, AL to Samuel F. Jarvis, 1795-1820 (Box 11, Folder 431)
  - Keogh, Andrew: "The Librarian as a Unifier" (typescript of speech with written corrections), 1915 (Box 11, Folder 432)
  - Ketcham, Henry H.: ALS to Mr. Elder, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 433)
  - King, William Lyon MacKenzie: TLS to Emerson Tuttle, ALS to Miss Havemeyer, 1915, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 434)
  - Kingsbury, Frederick J.: ALS from Franklin B. Dexter, TLS from Allen M. Hiller, 1906, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 435)
  - Kingsbury, Frederick J.: 4 AL from various correspondents, 1875-1891, 1903 (Box 11, Folder 436)
  - Kingsley, James L.: Transferred to Kingsley Papers, Mss 604 (Box 11, Folder 437)
  - Kitchel, Allan F.: bill to Yale College, 1905 (Box 11, Folder 438)
  - Kitchel, Cornelius L.: ALS to Arthur Twining Hadley, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 439)
  - Knapp, Jared Owen: ALS to Enoch Knapp, 1839 (Box 12, Folder 440)
  - Robertson, Arthur C.: La doctrine du General de Gaulle et les enseignements de l'histoire, thèsse pour le Doctorat d'Universitépresentée à la... (Box 12, Folder 441)
  - Knight, George H.: ALS to G. Eliot from Kate B. Knight (Mrs. George H.), 1926 (Box 12, Folder 442)
  - Knight, Jonathan: ALS to Nehemiah Colby, ALS from Edward Delafield, 1820, 1834 (Box 12, Folder 443)
  - Knopf, Adolph: Transferred to Adolph Knopf Papers, Mss 1253 (Box 12, Folder 444)
  - Knox, James: ALS to T.E. [Cresson?], 1855 (Box 12, Folder 445)
  - Kornreich, Jerome S.: typescript "On the Art of Cheating", undated (Box 12, Folder 446)
  - Kunz, George F.: letters from various Yale graduates, 1892-1926 (Box 12, Folder 447)
  - Kybal, Vlastimil: biographical sketch, letters to Leonard W. Labaree describing his work at Yale, 1944-1946 (Box 12, Folder 448)
  - Labatt, Henry J.: photostat of ALS to Rev. Isaac Lesser, 1849 (Box 12, Folder 449)
  - Ladd, George T.: ALS to Dr. Bacon: Transferred to George T. Ladd Papers, Mss 1371, undated (Box 12, Folder 450)
  - LaFarge, L. Bancel: Transferred to LaFarge Family Papers, Mss 24 (Box 12, Folder 451)
  - Lanman, James: ALS to Lewis [Pist?], 3 ALS to Mary Anne Ely, notebook of docket entries, 1809-1814, 1840 (Box 12, Folder 452)
  - Lathrop, Samuel: ALS to Justin Ely, 1809 (Box 12, Folder 453)
  - Lathrop, William M.: diary, 1823-1824 (Box 12, Folder 454)
  - Lawrence, Roderick: ALS from his father, John Lawrence, 1774 (Box 12, Folder 455)
  - Lawton, Sanford: transcript of letter to John Lawton, 1821 (Box 12, Folder 456)
  - Leavens, Dickson H.: Transferred to Dickson H. Leavens Papers, Mss 715 (Box 12, Folder 457)
  - Leavenworth, Elias W.: ALS to [Ben P. Poore?], 1875 (Box 12, Folder 458)